[
  {
    "question": "Who developed Python Programming Language?",
    "options": {
      "a": "Wick van Rossum",
      "b": "Rasmus Lerdorf",
      "c": "Guido van Rossum",
      "d": "Niene Stom"
    },
    "answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of Programming does Python support?",
    "options": {
      "a": "object-oriented programming",
      "b": "structured programming",
      "c": "functional programming",
      "d": "all of the mentioned"
    },
    "answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is Python case sensitive when dealing with identifiers?",
    "options": {
      "a": "no",
      "b": "yes",
      "c": "machine dependent",
      "d": "none of the mentioned"
    },
    "answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the correct extension of the Python file?",
    "options": {
      "a": ".python",
      "b": ".pl",
      "c": ".py",
      "d": ".p"
    },
    "answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is Python code compiled or interpreted?",
    "options": {
      "a": "Python code is both compiled and interpreted",
      "b": "Python code is neither compiled nor interpreted",
      "c": "Python code is only compiled",
      "d": "Python code is only interpreted"
    },
    "answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "All keywords in Python are in _________",
    "options": {
      "a": "Capitalized",
      "b": "lower case",
      "c": "UPPER CASE",
      "d": "None of the mentioned"
    },
    "answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What will be the value of the following Python expression?\n\nprint(4 + 3 % 5)",
    "options": {
      "a": "7",
      "b": "2",
      "c": "4",
      "d": "1"
    },
    "answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is used to define a block of code in Python language?",
    "options": {
      "a": "Indentation",
      "b": "Key",
      "c": "Brackets",
      "d": "All of the mentioned"
    },
    "answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which keyword is used for function in Python language?",
    "options": {
      "a": "Function",
      "b": "def",
      "c": "Fun",
      "d": "Define"
    },
    "answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following character is used to give single-line comments in Python?",
    "options": {
      "a": "//",
      "b": "#",
      "c": "!",
      "d": "/*"
    },
    "answer": "b"
  }
]
